london.gov.uk 2012-10-30

# The Greater London Authority’s Commitment to Privacy | Greater London Authority

  * Introduction
  * The information we collect about you
  * How we use your information
  * Protecting your information
  * Use of cookies and how you can disable them
  * Finding out what information the GLA holds about you
  * Changes to our Privacy Policy
  * Contacting the GLA about this Privacy Policy

## ****Introduction

The GLA is committed to protecting your privacy and processing your personal data in accordance with the Data Protection Act (DPA) 1998. This policy explains how information we collect about you is used and kept secure, your privacy choices when using our website, and your right to access your information under the DPA.

## ****The information we collect about you

Through our website, and the mayor@london.gov.uk email address we may collect the following information about you:

  * Your name, email address, postal address and any other information you voluntarily provide to us via our online enquiry forms. 
  * Your IP address (unique identifiers that computers or other devices use to identify and communicate with each other) that is automatically recognised by the web server.

## ****How we use your information

We may use your personal information for a number of purposes, including:

  * To deal with your requests and enquiries.
  * To contact you for reasons related to your enquiry.
  * To notify you about updates to the [www.london.gov.uk](http://www.london.gov.uk/) website. 
  * To use your IP address to monitor traffic and gather browsing behaviours of visitors to our websites. We will not use your IP address to identify you in any way. 
  * To create meaningful, actionable analysis that will help us to understand how policy issues and the Mayor and the GLA are being talked about and to react accordingly.

Your personal information will not be used for marketing purposes or any other services unless you have specifically agreed to be contacted for these purposes.

Public correspondence with the Mayor is stored in a system called WriteOn. In order that the Mayor can capture accurate, insightful information about the wants and needs of Londoners, this information is supplied to a third party (ResoLex Limited) to produce reports using bespoke software analysing the nature of the correspondence received. As part of this, personal data (name and address) from WriteON will be supplied. ResoLex Limited is contractually obliged to keep this information secure and not to use it for any purpose other than to provide analysis of the correspondence received to the GLA. Final reports are anonymised so no individuals can be identified.

If you would prefer the GLA not to share your personal data with ResoLex Limited for this purpose please state this in any correspondence you send and we will ensure your details are not shared.

Outside of the WriteOn system we will only share your personal information with a third party if required to do so by law or for the purposes of crime prevention or detection.

## ****Protecting your information

We have appropriate technical and organisational measures in place to prevent the loss, misuse or alteration of your personal information.

Any personal information you provide to us is stored securely on password and firewall protected servers and all website transactions are protected using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) encryption technology.

However, the Internet is not generally a secure medium for communication and therefore we cannot guarantee the security of any information you send to us over the Internet.

## ****Use of cookies and how you can disable them

A cookie is a piece of text that a website transfers to your computer’s hard disk so that it can remember who you are. They make interaction between your computer and our website faster and easier by remembering any registration details and preferences from previous visits. A cookie will typically contain the name of the website from which the cookie has come, the lifetime of the cookie and a value. It does not give us access to the rest of your computer and only the site that created the cookie can read it.

We use the following types of cookie:

Session cookies: to ensure you are recognised when you move from page to page within our site and that any information you enter is remembered.

Persistent cookies: to recognise you as a unique visitor to our website so that we can tailor content to match your interests.

You can control cookies through your web browser, just click on browser settings to find out the options your chosen browser allows. If you’d like to learn more about cookies, including how they have been set and how to manage them, visit allaboutcookies.org

## ****YouTube cookies

We embed videos from our YouTube channel, therefore, due to YouTube’s privacy-enhanced policy you may find that cookies are set on your computer once you have clicked to play the videos. However YouTube don’t store personally-identifiable cookie information relating to playbacks of embedded videos when using their privacy-enhanced mode. You can find out more here:[http://support.google.com/youtube/bin/answer.py?hl=en-GB&answer=171780](http://support.google.com/youtube/bin/answer.py?hl=en-GB&answer=171780)

## ****Our search engine

In order to give you the results you are looking for when you search our website, we use a piece of hardware supplied by Google. It is connected to our server and is constantly indexing the content on our site. All search requests on our site are handled by this hardware, however the information is not passed on to any third parties including Google. If you would prefer not to be tracked by Google analytics you can opt out here: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>

## ****Finding out what information the GLA holds about you

Under the Data Protection Act 1998, you can ask to see any personal information that we hold about you. Such requests are called subject access requests. 

If you would like to make a subject access request, please contact the GLA’s Data Protection Officer:

Data Protection Officer  
Technology Group  
Greater London Authority  
City Hall  
The Queen’s Walk  
London SE1 2AA

You will also need to provide two forms of identification, for example, driving licence, utility bill or passport and, if appropriate, any particulars about the source or location of the information you are requesting.

## ****Links to other websites

This privacy notice does not cover the links within this site linking to other websites. We encourage you to read the privacy statements on the other websites you visit.

## ****Changes to our Privacy Policy

We regularly review our Privacy Policy and updates will appear on this page when necessary. This Privacy Policy was last updated on 25 May 2012.

## ****Contacting the GLA about this Privacy Policy

If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Policy please write to us:

Information Governance Manager  
Greater London Authority  
City Hall  
The Queen’s Walk  
London SE1 2AA

Message / Quote
